cfa.org 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy

This is the web site of The Cat Fanciers' Association, Inc. (CFA). Our postal address is 260 East Main Street, Alliance, OH 44601. Phone 330-680-4070. Fax 330-680-4633. Email [securityofficer@cfa.org](mailto:securityofficer@cfa.org)  

### **About this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy has been published to provide a clear and concise outline of how and when personal information is collected, disclosed, used, stored and otherwise handled by The Cat Fanciers' Association, Inc (CFA). The Policy relates to personal information collected by any means and by any technology. 

CFA treats the handling of your personal information very seriously. To that end, CFA has systems and procedures in place to protect your privacy in relation to the handling of your personal information. 

CFA's objective is to handle information responsibly and provide you with some control over the way information about you is handled. 

**   
1\. Collection of Personal Information **

Personal information is information or opinion from which an individual's identity may be ascertained. The nature of personal information collected by CFA through our web site generally comprises an individual's name and contact details (including address, phone, fax and e-mail). Such personal information is not maintained in our files, unless required for specific contest entry purposes, survey purposes, etc.. 

CFA collects information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information, contest entry information and/or site registrations, name and address, telephone number, fax number, payment information (e.g., credit card number and billing address). 

CFA also collects other types of personal information from time to time (eg. credit information), only for purposes of online catalog sales, registration fees, etc. 

CFA does not collect personal information unless it is necessary for CFA to perform one or more of its functions and activities. CFA will destroy personal information when it is no longer required for such functions and activities. 

CFA will generally collect personal information from you directly. For example, CFA may collect personal information via telephone or letter, when you attend a function or event, request printed information or specific mailings, enter a competition, or provide a resume. 

**   
2\. Use & Disclosure of Personal Information **

Personal information provided to CFA may be shared with related committees within CFA, where it will be kept strictly confidential and will only be disclosed on a need-to-know basis. CFA will only use and disclose your personal information for the purpose for which the personal information was initially collected. 

CFA may also use that personal information for a purpose related to the initial purpose of collection if that other purpose would be within your reasonable expectations. Related purposes might include adding your name to a contact list, email notification or invitation list. 

CFA will not use or disclose your personal information for any other purposes without first obtaining your express or implied consent. CFA may however be required to disclose your personal information without your consent if the disclosure is:   
a. required or authorized by law;   
b. required in order to investigate an unlawful activity;   
c. required by an enforcement body for investigative activities; or   
d. necessary to prevent a serious and imminent threat to a person's life, health or safety, or to public health or safety. 

**   
3\. Direct Marketing **

From time to time CFA may use your personal information to identify activities which may be of interest to you to send you information regarding products available through CFA's business partners. 

If you do not wish to receive direct marketing information, please let CFA know. CFA will take immediate steps to ensure that you do not receive any direct marketing information in future. 

**   
4\. Ad Servers **

CFA does not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies. 

**   
5\. Cookies**

CFA uses cookies to store visitor preferences, record session information, such as items that consumers add to their shopping cart, secure area login data, etc. 

**   
6\. Personal Information Security**

CFA is committed to keeping your personal information secure, and we will take all reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, loss, misuse or alteration. 

Your personal information may be stored in hard copy documents, or electronically on CFA's software or systems. 

CFA maintains physical security over its paper and electronic data stores, such as locks and security systems. CFA also maintains computer and network security using passwords to control and restrict access to authorized staff for approved purposes. 

**   
7\. Access To Personal Information **

You may request access to the personal information CFA holds about you. 

The procedure for gaining access is as follows:   
a. All requests for access to your personal information must be made in writing and addressed to the Executive Director.   
b. You must provide as much detail as possible regarding the business entity, department or person to whom you believe your personal information has been provided, and when. This will allow CFA to process your request faster.   
c. CFA will acknowledge your request within 14 days, and access will usually be granted within 14 days, or if it is more complicated, 30 days. CFA will inform you if this timeframe is not achievable.   
d. You will be asked to verify your identity.   
e. A fee may apply to such access in the event that a request for access is onerous or time consuming. Such a fee will cover staff costs involved in locating and collating information, and reproduction costs.   
f. Depending on the circumstances, you may be forwarded the information by mail or email, or you may be required to personally inspect your records at the appropriate place.   
g. You will be given the opportunity to correct any personal information which is no longer accurate. 

In some circumstances, CFA may not be in a position to provide access. Such circumstances include where:   
a. providing access will have an unreasonable impact upon the privacy of other individuals;   
b. denying access is required or authorized by law;   
c. the request is frivolous;   
d. legal proceedings are underway;   
e. negotiations may be prejudiced by such access; or   
f. access would reveal a commercially sensitive decision making process. 

If CFA denies access to your personal information, it will provide you with reasons in writing. 

**   
8\. Changes To This Policy **

CFA may change this Policy from time to time for any reason and will update the Policy accordingly. 

**   
9\. Complaints**

If you believe that your privacy has been infringed you are entitled to complain. All complaints should initially be in writing and directed to the Executive Director. CFA will respond to your complaint as soon as possible, within 14 working days, to let you know who is responsible for managing your query. CFA will try to resolve the complaint within 30 working days. When this is not possible CFA will contact you to provide an estimate of how long it will take to handle the complaint. 

The Cat Fanciers' Association, Inc.   
Attention: Security Officer  
260 East Main Street  
Alliance, OH 44601
